Chapter 31.
Queen Mab.
Next morning, Stub accosted flask. Such a queer dream, King Post, I never had.
You know the old man's ivory leg. Well, I dreamed he kicked me with it. And when
I tried to kick back upon my soul, my little man, I kicked my leg right off.
And then presto, Ahab seemed a pyramid, and I, like a blazing fool, kept kicking
at it. But what was still more curious, flask, you know how curious all dreams
are. Through all this rage that I was in, I somehow seemed to be thinking to
myself that after all it was not much of an insult that kick from Ahab. Why
thinks I What's the row? It's not a real leg, only a false leg. And there's a
mighty difference between a living thump and a dead thump. That's what makes a
blow from the hand flask 50 times more savage to bear than a blow from a cane.
The living member, that makes the living insult, my little man. and thinks I to
myself all the while mind while I was stubbing my silly toes against that
cursed pyramid. So confoundedly contradictory was it all all the while I
say I was thinking to myself, what's his leg now but a cane? A whale bone cane?
Yes, thinks I was only a playful cudgling. In fact, only a whale boning
that he gave me, not a base kick.
Besides, think I look at it once. Why, the end of it, the foot part, what a
small sort of end it is. Whereas if a broad-footed farmer kicked me, there's a
devilish broad insult. But this insult is whittleled down to a point only. But
now comes the greatest joke of the dream. Flask. While I was battering away
at the pyramid, a sort of badger-haired old merman with a hump on his back takes
me by the shoulders and slews me round.
What are you about? Says he slid man.
But I was frightened. Such a fizz. But somehow next moment I was over the
fright. What am I about? Says I at last.
And what business is that of yours? I should like to know, Mr. Humpback. Do
you want a kick? By the Lord, flask, I had no sooner said that than he turned
round his stern to me, bent over, and dragging up a lot of seaweed he had for
a clout. What do you think I saw? Why, thunder alive, man. His stern was stuck
full of marlin spikes with the points out. says I on second thoughts. I guess
I won't kick you, old fellow. Wise stub, says he, wise stub, and kept muttering
it all the time. A sort of eating of his own gums like a chimney hag. Seeing he
wasn't going to stop saying over his wise stub, wise stub. I thought I might
as well fall to kicking the pyramid again. But I had only just lifted my
foot for it when he roared out, stop that kicking. Hello, says I. What's the
matter now, old fellow? Look ye here, says he. Let's argue the insult. Captain
Ahab kicked you, didn't he? Yes, he did, says I. Right here it was. Very good,
says he. He used his ivory leg, didn't he? Yes, he did, says I. Well, then,
says he, wise stub. What have you to complain of? Didn't he kick you with
right goodwill? It wasn't a common pitchpine leg he kicked with, was it?
No, you were kicked by a great man and with a beautiful ivory leg, Stub. It's
an honor. I consider it an honor.
Listen, wise Stub. In old England, the greatest lords think it great glory to
be slapped by a queen and made guarder knights of. But be your bow, Stub, that
ye were kicked by old Ahab and made a wise man of. Remember what I say. Be
kicked by him. Account his kicks honors and on no account kick back. for you
can't help yourself, wise stub. Don't you see that pyramid? With that, he all
of a sudden seemed somehow in some queer fashion to swim off into the air. I
snored, rolled over, and there I was in my hammock. Now, what do you think of
that dream, Flask?
I don't know. It seems sort of foolish to me, though. Maybe, maybe. But it's
made a wise man of me. Flask. Do you see Ahab standing there sideways looking
over the stern? Well, the best thing you can do, Flask, is to let the old man
alone. Never speak to him, whatever, he says. Hello. What's that? He shouts.
Hark mast head there. Look sharp all of you. There are whales here. If you see a
white one, split your lungs for him.
What do you think of that now, Flask?
Ain't there a small drop of something queer about that? Eh, a white whale. Did
you mark that, man? Look ye, there's something special in the wind. Stand by
for it, flask. Ahab has that that's bloody on his mind. But mom, he comes this way.